<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:53:42 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A software for modern statistical process monitoring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/package-spm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/package-spm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I developed a software package in Julia designed for advanced statistical process monitoring. This package integrates state-of-the-art algorithms with modern control charts to monitor complex data structures, including sequential data, functional data, and networks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The software is designed for real-time monitoring and early detection of anomalies, offering versatile applications across various industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring of complex geometrical shapes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/ovetti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/ovetti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I developed an innovative statistical quality control method for detecting shape defects in complex geometries obtained via Additive Manufacturing.&#xA;I created a novel non-parametric control chart based on kurtosis analysis to enhancing defect sensitivity and improving monitoring of 3D-printed objects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Scientist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/data-scientist-at-optit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/data-scientist-at-optit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-scientist-at-optit-srl&#34;&gt;Data Scientist at OPTIT S.r.l.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I joined OPTIT S.r.l. as a Data Scientist to leverage my statistical expertise to solve complex, real-world problems. My goal is to drive innovation in logistics and supply chain optimization by applying cutting-edge machine learning techniques and developing novel, data-driven solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D. Student</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;phd-student-in-statistical-sciences&#34;&gt;Ph.D. Student in Statistical Sciences&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my Ph.D. in Statistical Sciences at Università degli Studi di Padova, I focused on advancing my technical expertise in industrial statistics, particularly in real-time outlier detection and stochastic optimization. My work in these areas has been recognized through multiple publications in leading journals, such as &lt;em&gt;Journal of Quality Technology&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Quality Engineering&lt;/em&gt;.&#xA;Furthermore, I developed a statistical package in &lt;strong&gt;Julia&lt;/strong&gt;, which has been published as an article in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Statistical Software&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
